const quizQuestions17en = [{
    question:"Regarding electroslag welding (ESW), it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["Heat is generated by passing current through the weld pool.",
    "It is possible to weld sections over 20 cm thick.",
    "Shoes are unnecessary for this process when the sheets are positioned horizontally.",
    "The ESW process is very economical as it can take advantage of the flux used in SAW process (but it must be of the active type)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Compared to the solid wire MIG/MAG process, flux cored wire welding (FCAW) can offer:",
    answers: ["better base metal wettability when welding aluminium alloys;",
    "better base metal wettability when welding stainless steels;",
    "lower spatter generation;",
    "a possibility of welding thinner sheets."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Compared to the solid wire MIG/MAG process, flux cored wire welding (FCAW) can offer:",
    answers: ["better base metal wettability when welding aluminium alloys;",
    "lower spatter generation;",
    "a possibility of welding thinner sheets;",
    "higher penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Among these processes used in additive manufacturing, which is the most suitable for building a valve in the shape of a hollow tube with a diameter of 10 mm and a thickness of 2 mm?",
    answers: ["GTAW (TIG welding).",
    "GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    " Laser directed energy deposition (L-DED).",
    "Selective Laser Melting."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a characteristic of robotic MIG/MAG welding application:",
    answers: ["The deposition rate becomes higher.",
    "Reduction of manufacturing costs, especially in smaller-scale production.",
    "The robot can perform some welds that are impossible for a welder to perform.",
    "Non-productive time is reduced as the robot can be operated 24 hours a day."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a characteristic of robotic MIG/MAG welding application:",
    answers: ["The deposition rate becomes higher.",
    "Robot application efficiency is lower when the robot is programmed on-line for short welds.",
    "Reduction of manufacturing costs, especially in smaller-scale production.",
    "The robot can perform some welds that are impossible for a welder to perform."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a characteristic of robotic MIG/MAG welding application:",
    answers: ["The deposition rate becomes higher.",
    "Reduction of manufacturing costs, especially in smaller-scale production.",
    "It is desirable that the joint be redesigned for robotic welding.",
    "The robot can perform some welds that are impossible for a welder to perform."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The laser (LBW) and electron beam (EBW) welding processes are characterized by the following characteristic:",
    answers: ["They tolerate large root gaps between sheets to be welded.",
    "They offer a high penetration/width ratio.",
    "They are easily handled during manual welding.",
    "They use a more expensive filler metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The lobe curve (Current x Time) in resistance spot welding represents:",
    answers: ["A function between the current value in the primary and the duration of the alternating current half-cycle.",
    "A function between the current value in the secondary and the duration of the alternating current half-cycle.",
    "A relationship between welding current and welding time at which acceptable quality welding points are obtained.",
    "A relationship between current and welding time with the same energy generated (the same heat generated)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In the case of SAW process with a Constant Voltage power source, the operator has reached the limit of the wire feed speed of the equipment. How to increase the current even more?",
    answers: ["To increase the contact tip-to-work distance (if allowed by EPS) while continuing to use the maximum wire feed speed.",
    "To reduce the contact tip-to-work distance (if allowed by EPS), while still using the maximum wire feed speed.",
    "To change the wire to a smaller diameter (if allowed by EPS), continuing to use the maximum wire feed speed.",
    "Increase the no-load voltage of the power source, maintaining the same arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In the case of SAW process with a Constant Voltage power source, the operator has reached the limit of the wire feed speed of the equipment. How to increase the current even more?",
    answers: ["To increase the contact tip-to-work distance (if allowed by EPS) while continuing to use the maximum wire feed speed.",
    "To change the wire to a smaller diameter (if allowed by EPS), continuing to use the maximum wire feed speed.",
    "To change the wire for a larger diameter (if allowed by EPS), reducing the wire feed speed to the appropriate value.",
    "Increase the no-load voltage of the power source, maintaining the same arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of galvanized (zinc plated) sheets when using resistance spot welding, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The burning of zinc in galvanized sheets (burn-zinc operation) is achieved by using a cycle with high current (above the level of the welding current) for a short time before making the spot weld.",
    "The zinc layers do not present any difficulty, because, thanks to a low melting and boiling points, the zinc evaporates before the melting point of the steel is reached.",
    "One of the advantages of resistance welding galvanized sheets is a good electrical contact between the sheets.",
    "The burning of zinc (burn-zinc operation) is achieved applying a low current pulse for a short time before making the spot weld."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Plasma arc welding process (PAW) it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "The constricting nozzle orifice diameter is one of the main factors for increasing the plasma jet velocity.",
    "A high flow rate of plasma gas is the main factor in ensuring the physical constriction of the arc (narrow columnar profile of the arc).",
    "A high arc voltage is one of the main factors for increasing plasma jet speed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Plasma arc welding process (PAW) it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "A high flow rate of plasma gas is the main factor in ensuring the physical constriction of the arc (narrow columnar profile of the arc).",
    "A high arc voltage is one of the main factors for increasing plasma jet speed.",
    "Plasma gas is typically of a low flow rate, in the order of 0.25 to 5 l/min."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Comparing the electroslag (ESW) and electrogas (EGW) processes, it is possible to state that:",
    answers: ["The electrogas process requires a slightly more complex shoe, as it needs to provide for the inlet and distribution of the shielding gas, in addition to cooling.",
    "Only the electroslag process generates large columnar grains and extensive HAZ, as the energy is less concentrated.",
    "The electroslag process requires gas to protect the slag against atmospheric oxidation.",
    "The ESW process can only be used in the flat position, while the EGW process can be applied in any welding position."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Comparing the electroslag (ESW) and electrogas (EGW) processes, it is possible to state that:",
    answers: ["Only the electroslag process generates large columnar grains and extensive HAZ, as the energy is less concentrated.",
    "One of the limitations of the electrogas process is the logistics of having the necessary shielding gas for the process.",
    "The electroslag process requires gas to protect the slag against atmospheric oxidation.",
    "The ESW process can only be used in the flat position, while the EGW process can be applied in any welding position."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Stud Welding (SW) process, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["There are two versions of the SW process: Capacitor Discharge Stud Welding and Resistance Stud Welding.",
    "The process has a low execution time, taking on average less than 1 s, from the positioning of the gun until the stud is released.",
    "It is not possible to weld dissimilar materials.",
    "An important advantage of the process is that the stud can be welded onto painted and galvanized surfaces."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Stud Welding (SW) process, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["There are two versions of the SW process: Capacitor Discharge Stud Welding and Resistance Stud Welding.",
    "It is not possible to weld dissimilar materials.",
    "There are two versions of this process: Arc Stud Welding and Capacitor Discharge Stud Welding.",
    "An important advantage of the process is that the stud can be welded onto painted and galvanized surfaces."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Stud Welding (SW) process, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["There are two versions of the SW process: Capacitor Discharge Stud Welding and Resistance Stud Welding.",
    "It is not possible to weld dissimilar materials.",
    "An important advantage of the process is that the stud can be welded onto painted and galvanized surfaces.",
    "The stud can be circular or rectangular in profile and can be hollow or solid, ranging from heavy support studs to spacer studs."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What would you do if you need to reduce penetration in MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["I would reduce the arc voltage.",
    "\"I would change the welding technique from \"\"forehand\"\" (\"\"pushing\"\") to \"\"backhand\"\" (\"\"pulling\"\").\"",
    "It would increase the contact tip-to-work distance.",
    "I would change the shielding gas to a CO2-rich mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the high frequency resistance welding process, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["There are two versions of this process depending on the method of generating the high frequency current in the parts to be welded: the current is introduced by sliding electrodes or the current is induced by an induction coil.",
    "High frequency resistance welding is classified as a fusion welding process.",
    "The maximum frequency applied in induction welding does not exceed 50 kHz.",
    "\"One of the disadvantages of this welding process is that the high frequency current tends to concentrate on the outer surface of the conductor (\"\"skin effect\"\"), thus reducing the efficiency of heating the base metal.\""],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the high frequency resistance welding process, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["High frequency resistance welding is classified as a fusion welding process.",
    "Butt and corner joints can be welded by this process.",
    "The maximum frequency applied in induction welding does not exceed 50 kHz.",
    "\"One of the disadvantages of this welding process is that the high frequency current tends to concentrate on the outer surface of the conductor (\"\"skin effect\"\"), thus reducing the efficiency of heating the base metal.\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the high frequency resistance welding process, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["High frequency resistance welding is classified as a fusion welding process.",
    "The maximum frequency applied in induction welding does not exceed 50 kHz.",
    "In the case of induction welding, the higher the frequency imposed, the smaller the current conduction zone obtained in the part, thus increasing the current density.",
    "\"One of the disadvantages of this welding process is that the high frequency current tends to concentrate on the outer surface of the conductor (\"\"skin effect\"\"), thus reducing the efficiency of heating the base metal.\""],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the high frequency resistance welding process, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["High frequency resistance welding is classified as a fusion welding process.",
    "The maximum frequency applied in induction welding does not exceed 50 kHz.",
    "\"One of the disadvantages of this welding process is that the high frequency current tends to concentrate on the outer surface of the conductor (\"\"skin effect\"\"), thus reducing the efficiency of heating the base metal.\"",
    "\"The name of this method can be added by \"\"induction\"\", if the current is induced by an induction coil.\""],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct statements regarding the thermal spraying processes.",
    answers: ["The basic variations of thermal spraying processes occur in the materials used, in the heating method and in the method of propelling the materials to the substrate.",
    "Substrate preparation (surface cleaning) is basically done by cathodic cleaning.",
    "Thermally sprayed coatings never receive post-spray treatments.",
    "The joining between the coating and the substrate is basically a mechanical anchoring bonding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct statements regarding the thermal spraying processes.",
    answers: ["Substrate preparation (surface cleaning) is basically done by cathodic cleaning.",
    "Substrate preparation prior to spraying is required for all process variations and the two important steps are cleaning the surface and generating adequate roughness.",
    "Thermally sprayed coatings never receive post-spray treatments.",
    "The joining between the coating and the substrate is basically a mechanical anchoring bonding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct statements regarding the thermal spraying processes.",
    answers: ["Substrate preparation (surface cleaning) is basically done by cathodic cleaning.",
    "Thermally sprayed coatings never receive post-spray treatments.",
    "The bond between the coating and the substrate is influenced by factors such as the surface temperature before, during and after spraying and particle impact velocity.",
    "The joining between the coating and the substrate is basically a mechanical anchoring bonding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct statements regarding the thermal spraying processes.",
    answers: ["Substrate preparation (surface cleaning) is basically done by cathodic cleaning.",
    "Thermally sprayed coatings never receive post-spray treatments.",
    "The joining between the coating and the substrate is basically a mechanical anchoring bonding.",
    "The bond between the coating and the substrate may be mechanical, chemical, metallurgical, physical or a combination of these."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct statements regarding the thermal spraying processes.",
    answers: ["Substrate preparation (surface cleaning) is basically done by cathodic cleaning.",
    "Thermally sprayed coatings never receive post-spray treatments.",
    "The bond between the coating and the substrate is influenced by factors such as coating material, substrate condition, degree of surface roughness and cleanliness.",
    "The joining between the coating and the substrate is basically a mechanical anchoring bonding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is a characteristic of electronic power sources, mainly of the inverter type, but not of electromagnetic power sources (transformer-rectifiers):",
    answers: ["High frequency arc striking.",
    "The easiness of interfacing with automatic equipment.",
    "They allow to increase the welding current (for example, from 100 A to 120 A) without causing an increase in the energy consumption of the supply network.",
    "Inductance adjustment."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is a characteristic of electronic power sources, mainly of the inverter type, but not of electromagnetic power sources (transformer-rectifiers):",
    answers: ["High frequency arc striking.",
    "They allow to increase the welding current (for example, from 100 A to 120 A) without causing an increase in the energy consumption of the supply network.",
    "Inductance adjustment.",
    "They consume less energy from the supply network working at the same level of welding current."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the particularity of supplying filler metal in the submerged arc welding (SAW) process, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The filler metal is supplied in the form of solid or tubular wires, through single or multiple electrode configurations, as well as, in special techniques (in surfacing), in the form of metallic strip.",
    "In the SAW process, in special applications, filler metal can be additionally supplied in the form of iron powder, which is mixed with the flux before the flux is applied.",
    "In SAW welding, the cold wire addition technique is not applicable due to the risk of generating metallic inclusions.",
    "The hot wire addition technique works well, but only if those wires are thin (in the range of 1.0 - 1.2 mm)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of brazing/soldering joining over fusion welding:",
    answers: ["Make it possible to carry out any type of joint (but, lap, Tee, Edge and Corner joint).",
    "More heat, but lower temperature are required than in welding by the same heating method.",
    "Filler metal is of lower cost.",
    "Ability to preserve coatings on the base metal (without burning)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of brazing/soldering joining over fusion welding:",
    answers: ["Make it possible to carry out any type of joint (but, lap, Tee, Edge and Corner joint);",
    "Ability to join metals with non-metallic materials;",
    "More heat, but lower temperature are required than in welding by the same heating method;",
    "Filler metal is of lower cost."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the true alternative regarding welding processes:",
    answers: ["In electroslag welding (ESW), the shoes must be of the same material as the plates to be welded, to ensure uniformity of the joint.",
    "By electroslag welding (ESW), it is possible to weld sections of large thickness (higher than 30 mm) in the flat position (vertical upwards progression or approximately to this).",
    "In Friction Stir Welding, the tool is consumed as the weld is being performed.",
    "In electrogas welding (EGW), the shoes must be of the same metal as the workpieces, as they form part of the joint."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the true alternative regarding welding processes:",
    answers: ["In electroslag welding (ESW), the shoes must be of the same material as the plates to be welded, to ensure uniformity of the joint.",
    "In Friction Stir Welding, the tool is consumed as the weld is being performed.",
    "In electrogas welding (EGW), the shoes must be of the same material as the plates to be welded, as they form part of the joint.",
    "Friction welding is based on frictional relative motion between parts, that is, one can be immobile."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding filler metals for brazing/soldering, mark the correct statement:",
    answers: ["Generally speaking, a short melting temperature range filler metal is more suitable for large gap joints.",
    "Copper alloys (e.g., copper-zinc) are used in joining all ferrous and non-ferrous materials, in lap or butt joints, with different heating methods.",
    "Gold and its alloys are used for brazing iron, nickel and cobalt when oxidation resistance is required or in applications where volatile components are undesirable.",
    "The most suitable filler metal for soldering is lead."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding filler metals for brazing/soldering, mark the correct statement:",
    answers: ["Silver-based filler metals are used for joining many ferrous and non-ferrous metals and can be used with all heating methods.",
    "Generally speaking, a short melting temperature range filler metal is more suitable for large gap joints.",
    "Copper alloys (e.g., copper-zinc) are used in joining all ferrous and non-ferrous materials, in lap or butt joints, with different heating methods.",
    "The most suitable filler metal for soldering is lead."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a typical characteristic of Hot Gas Welding of Plastics:",
    answers: ["The most commonly used in this process are compressed air, nitrogen, hydrogen, oxygen and carbon dioxide.",
    "Welding consists of blowing a stream of heated gas over the surface to be welded until it begins to melt. Then, the thermoplastic welding rod is forced into the molten pool, thus promoting welding.",
    "Type, temperature and gas flow rate, the angle formed between the filler rod and the base material and the welding speed are the process variables to be controlled.",
    "Type, temperature and gas flow rate, as well as the feeding speed are the process variables to be controlled."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a typical characteristic of Hot Gas Welding of Plastics:",
    answers: ["The joint design is similar to that used in filler arc welding and includes butt, corner and lap joints, which are bevelled in the same manner as metals.",
    "The most commonly used in this process are compressed air, nitrogen, hydrogen, oxygen and carbon dioxide.",
    "Welding consists of blowing a stream of heated gas over the surface to be welded until it begins to melt. Then, the thermoplastic welding rod is forced into the molten pool, thus promoting welding.",
    "Type, temperature and gas flow rate, as well as the feeding speed are the process variables to be controlled."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a typical characteristic of Hot Gas Welding of Plastics:",
    answers: ["The most commonly used in this process are compressed air, nitrogen, hydrogen, oxygen and carbon dioxide.",
    "Welding consists of blowing a stream of heated gas, usually air, to heat and melt both the thermoplastic substrate material and the thermoplastic welding rod. Then the filler material is forced into the joint, thus promoting welding.",
    "Welding consists of blowing a stream of heated gas over the surface to be welded until it begins to melt. Then, the thermoplastic welding rod is forced into the molten pool, thus promoting welding.",
    "Type, temperature and gas flow rate, as well as the feeding speed are the process variables to be controlled."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative with regard to welding plastics.",
    answers: ["Ultrasonic welding is indicated for joining large parts.",
    "Increased productivity in hot plate welding is achieved by employing higher temperatures and longer heating times.",
    "Fusion welding processes are the most suitable for welding plastics.",
    "When welding with hot gas, the welding plastic rod must not be melted completely."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors used in automatic welding:",
    answers: ["Sensors based on the arc electrical signal (voltage or current), so called “through-the-arc sensors”, are used for both joint tracking and for the contact tip-to-work distance control.",
    "Contact sensors for joint tracking (joint trackers) cannot be used in fusion welding as heat damages them.",
    "The laser to be used as a sensor in welding must be of the Nd:YAG or CO2 type.",
    "The heat produced by the arc and spatter do not pose any risk to the correct operation of the sensors in welding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors used in automatic welding:",
    answers: ["Contact sensors for joint tracking (joint trackers) cannot be used in fusion welding as heat damages them.",
    "The laser sensor can be used effectively for both joint tracking and to evaluate the groove geometry/joint surface.",
    "The laser to be used as a sensor in welding must be of the Nd:YAG or CO2 type.",
    "The heat produced by the arc and spatter do not pose any risk to the correct operation of the sensors in welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of the FCAW process over the GMAW process using the same gas CO2:",
    answers: ["Lower spatter generation.",
    "Lower electrode metal losses from its burning.",
    "The wire feeder can be made simpler (with just two rollers).",
    "Welding in all positions."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of the FCAW process over the GMAW process using the same gas CO2:",
    answers: ["Lower electrode metal losses from its burning.",
    "Improved weld geometry.",
    "The wire feeder can be made simpler (with just two rollers).",
    "Welding in all positions."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of the FCAW process over the GMAW process using the same gas CO2:",
    answers: ["Lower electrode metal losses from its burning.",
    "The wire feeder can be made simpler (with just two rollers).",
    "Welding in all positions.",
    "Higher porosity resistance of the weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the welding process with tubular wires (MIG/MAG “metal cored”) and with tubular electrodes (flux cored arc welding, FCAW) it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["There are two basic variations of the FCAW with tubular wires (metal-cored), namely, with and without external gas shielding.",
    "In semi-automatic welding with tubular wires and tubular electrodes, it is highly recommended to use 4 rollers in the electrode wire feeding system.",
    "For the FCAW process it is necessary to use wire feeders and torches developed specifically for that.",
    "Because of difficulties in manufacturing tubular wires and electrodes, their diameters are 1.6 mm and higher (while solid wire diameters are usually within the range of 0.6 to 1.6 mm)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In resistance welding, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["In projection welding, the shape of the electrodes must conform to the shape of the projections.",
    "In resistance butt welding, the pressure is increased after the current is turned off, which causes an excess of material in the joint region.",
    "The pressure in spot welding must be as low as possible, as its function is to just position the parts (high pressure reduces the electrical resistance and, therefore, the heating at the interface).",
    "The pressure in spot welding should be high, as its function is to forge the parts after the current is turned off."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is one of the advantages of direct current power sources over alternating current power sources for resistance spot welding:",
    answers: ["They are larger and therefore more robust.",
    "They charge all three phases of the power network equally (whereas AC power sources use only two phases).",
    "They offer better control of penetration (it is higher on the negative electrode side).",
    "They offer better control of penetration (it is higher on the positive electrode side)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is one of the advantages of direct current power sources over alternating current power sources for resistance spot welding:",
    answers: ["They are larger and therefore more robust.",
    "They offer better control of penetration (it is higher on the negative electrode side).",
    "They offer better control of penetration (it is higher on the positive electrode side).",
    "They offer better dynamic control, as the adjustment time is in ms and not in cycles, making it possible to better discretize the times."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the true alternative, regarding the brazing/soldering process:",
    answers: ["There is no brazing/soldering without using the capillary effect.",
    "Brazing with a silver alloy, despite its lower mechanical strength, is often preferable to brazing with a Cu-Zn (brass) or Cu-Sn (bronze) alloy, as it has a lower melting point.",
    "The larger the gap, the easier the capillary effect and the higher the strength of the brazed joint.",
    "Aluminium, as it has a low melting point, cannot be brazed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is true regarding the plasma welding process?",
    answers: ["One of the properties of plasma gases that can influence the performance of plasma welding is their chemical reactivity (only inert or reducing gases can be used).",
    "In plasma welding, direct current with electrode negative polarity is always applied to all materials.",
    "Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "In general, it is the diameter of the constrictor hole that determines the arc concentration, so the electrode sharpening angle and its distance from the face of the constrictor nozzle hole are not important parameters."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is true regarding the plasma welding process?",
    answers: ["In plasma welding, direct current with electrode negative polarity is always applied to all materials.",
    "An increase in current leads to higher width and penetration of the weld bead.",
    "Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "In general, it is the diameter of the constrictor hole that determines the arc concentration, so the electrode sharpening angle and its distance from the face of the constrictor nozzle hole are not important parameters."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is true regarding the plasma welding process?",
    answers: ["In plasma welding, direct current with electrode negative polarity is always applied to all materials.",
    "Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "In general, a reduction in the diameter of the constrictor orifice increases the concentration and pressure of the arc and, therefore, the penetration capacity.",
    "In general, it is the diameter of the constrictor hole that determines the arc concentration, so the electrode sharpening angle and its distance from the face of the constrictor nozzle hole are not important parameters."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is true regarding the plasma welding process?",
    answers: ["In plasma welding, direct current with electrode negative polarity is always applied to all materials.",
    "Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "The sharpening of the electrode in the Plasma process facilitates the emission of electrons by thermionic effect (higher heating for having less volume).",
    "In general, it is the diameter of the constrictor hole that determines the arc concentration, so the electrode sharpening angle and its distance from the face of the constrictor nozzle hole are not important parameters."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the classification of welding processes into “fusion” and “solid state” welding, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["In the processes classified as “Solid State Welding”, the phenomenon of diffusion has high importance.",
    "In order to have welding joining, it is always necessary to have an imposed thermal energy, except for the processes classified as “Solid State Welding”.",
    "\"The pressure, consequently the friction, is the driving force to generate the heat to carry out the welding of the processes classified as \"\"Solid State Welding\"\".\"",
    "All welding processes classified as “Fusion Welding” use the arc as the heat source."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The following is one of the advantages of Pulsed MIG welding:",
    answers: ["Possibility of using pure CO2 as a shielding gas.",
    "Possibility of using a large diameter wire electrode to weld thin sheets.",
    "High deposition rate.",
    "Higher penetration due to the mechanical action of the current pulse."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Friction Stir Welding, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["A rotating non-consumable tool is inserted between two facing workpieces to promote heating and coalescence.",
    "For thin sheets, it can be carried out in the semi-automatic version, with the rotating tool attached to a drill translated along the joint by the welder.",
    "A high degree plastic deformation imposed in the joint region causes distortions and very high residual stresses.",
    "\"In this welding process, there are no weld defect of the \"\"lack of fusion\"\" type, as the rotating tool softens both edges of the joint evenly.\""],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Friction Stir Welding, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["For thin sheets, it can be carried out in the semi-automatic version, with the rotating tool attached to a drill translated along the joint by the welder.",
    "It is a solid-state welding process (less heat input), normally with full penetration.",
    "A high degree plastic deformation imposed in the joint region causes distortions and very high residual stresses.",
    "\"In this welding process, there are no weld defect of the \"\"lack of fusion\"\" type, as the rotating tool softens both edges of the joint evenly.\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Friction Stir Welding, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["For thin sheets, it can be carried out in the semi-automatic version, with the rotating tool attached to a drill translated along the joint by the welder.",
    "A high degree plastic deformation imposed in the joint region causes distortions and very high residual stresses.",
    "No consumables and shielding gases are used in the process.",
    "\"In this welding process, there are no weld defect of the \"\"lack of fusion\"\" type, as the rotating tool softens both edges of the joint evenly.\""],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding arc welding surfacing techniques, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["Hardfacing is carried out only by coated electrode, as other processes cannot deposit the necessary alloying elements.",
    "Buttering is a coating operation whose function is to protect the surface against corrosion.",
    "Stainless steel layers are deposited on carbon steel substrate surfaces not to maintain the structural properties of the substrate, but to increase its corrosion resistance.",
    "The tubular electrode process is widely used for hardfacing, but only with a gas shielding, to minimize the losses of the alloying elements."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors, actuators and controllers used in mechanized and automated (robotized) welding processes.",
    answers: ["Actuators are components that convert electrical, hydraulic or pneumatic energy into mechanical energy.",
    "Actuators are components that convert mechanical, hydraulic or pneumatic energy into electrical energy.",
    "The sensor receives an electrical signal or stimulus (input signal) and responds with a mechanical signal (output signal).",
    "In an automatic system, the controller receives signals from actuators and controls the operation of sensors."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors, actuators and controllers used in mechanized and automated (robotized) welding processes.",
    answers: ["Actuators are components that convert mechanical, hydraulic or pneumatic energy into electrical energy.",
    "Sensors provide the control unit with information about the behaviour of the automatic system.",
    "The sensor receives an electrical signal or stimulus (input signal) and responds with a mechanical signal (output signal).",
    "In an automatic system, the controller receives signals from actuators and controls the operation of sensors."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors, actuators and controllers used in mechanized and automated (robotized) welding processes.",
    answers: ["Actuators are components that convert mechanical, hydraulic or pneumatic energy into electrical energy.",
    "The sensor receives an electrical signal or stimulus (input signal) and responds with a mechanical signal (output signal).",
    "Controllers are responsible for managing and monitoring the operating parameters required for the automatic system to carry out the expected tasks.",
    "In an automatic system, the controller receives signals from actuators and controls the operation of sensors."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors, actuators and controllers used in mechanized and automated (robotized) welding processes.",
    answers: ["Actuators are components that convert mechanical, hydraulic or pneumatic energy into electrical energy.",
    "The sensor receives an electrical signal or stimulus (input signal) and responds with a mechanical signal (output signal).",
    "In an automatic system, the controller receives signals from actuators and controls the operation of sensors.",
    "The movement commands coming from controllers and sent to the actuators are originated in the control unit and based on information obtained by the sensors."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors, actuators and controllers used in mechanized and automated (robotized) welding processes.",
    answers: ["The sensor receives a signal or stimulus (input signal that can be: presence or absence of light, heat, sound, gas, electric field, magnetic field, etc.) and responds with an electrical output signal.",
    "Actuators are components that convert mechanical, hydraulic or pneumatic energy into electrical energy.",
    "The sensor receives an electrical signal or stimulus (input signal) and responds with a mechanical signal (output signal).",
    "In an automatic system, the controller receives signals from actuators and controls the operation of sensors."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the particularity of supplying filler metal in the submerged arc welding (SAW) process, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The filler metal can be additionally supplied in the form of iron powder, which is mixed with the flux before its use.",
    "In SAW welding, the cold wire addition technique is not applicable due to the risk of generating metallic inclusions.",
    "In configurations with two electrode wires, they can be placed next to each other in a line perpendicular to the joint line (Twin Arc) or one behind the other in the welding direction (Tandem Arc).",
    "The hot wire addition technique works well in SAW welding, but only if those wires are thin (in the range of 1.0 - 1.2 mm) so as not to harm the metallurgy of the process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the particularity of supplying filler metal in the submerged arc welding (SAW) process, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The filler metal can be additionally supplied in the form of iron powder, which is mixed with the flux before its use.",
    "In SAW welding, the cold wire addition technique is not applicable due to the risk of generating metallic inclusions.",
    "The hot wire addition technique works well in SAW welding, but only if those wires are thin (in the range of 1.0 - 1.2 mm) so as not to harm the metallurgy of the process.",
    "For the SAW process, electrode wires with a diameter of 1.6 to 6.4 mm are used, the most common being 2.4 mm, 3.25 mm and 4.0 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the particularity of supplying filler metal in the submerged arc welding (SAW) process, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The filler metal can be additionally supplied in the form of iron powder, which is mixed with the flux before its use.",
    "In special applications of the SAW, the filler metal can be supplied additionally in the form of iron powder layer placed above the joint line before the flux (i.e., below the flux).",
    "In SAW welding, the cold wire addition technique is not applicable due to the risk of generating metallic inclusions.",
    "The hot wire addition technique works well in SAW welding, but only if those wires are thin (in the range of 1.0 - 1.2 mm) so as not to harm the metallurgy of the process."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative with regard to welding plastics.",
    answers: ["Ultrasonic welding is indicated for joining large parts.",
    "Thermosets are easily weldable.",
    "In hot gas welding, the joint design is similar to that used in welding of metals with a filler material.",
    "Fusion welding processes are the most suitable for welding plastics."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative with regard to welding plastics.",
    answers: ["Polymers are classified according to their behaviour at high temperatures and their chain structure.",
    "Thermosets are easily weldable.",
    "Fusion welding processes are the most suitable for welding plastics.",
    "Increased productivity in hot plate welding is achieved by employing higher temperatures and longer heating times."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the classification of polymers, it is possible to state:",
    answers: ["Polymers are divided into plastics, thermosets and duroplastics.",
    "Polymers are divided into elastomers, thermosets and polyplastics.",
    "Polymers are divided into elastomers, thermosets and thermoplastics.",
    "Polymers are divided into elastomers, thermosets and duroplastics."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "},
    {
    question:"The shape and position of the CCT (Continuous Cooling Transformation) curves of carbon steels are influenced by several factors. In this regard, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The addition of the absolute majority of alloying elements shifts these curves to the right and downwards, and may or may not change their shape.",
    "The larger the austenite grain size, the more to the left these curves are shifted.",
    "Higher austenitization temperatures as well as a higher holding time at that temperatures shift the curves to the right.",
    "Elements with strong affinity with carbon, such as Cr, Mo, Nb, Ti, V, etc., delay the ferritic-pearlite transformation and make the bainitic phase appear at higher temperatures."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding pure nickel with TIG process, which of the following is likely to minimize porosity?",
    answers: ["The use of an inert shielding gas with 2 - 3% nitrogen addition.",
    "The use of narrower groove angles (40 - 60 degrees) to reduce angular distortion.",
    "The use of a filler metal containing a small percentage of titanium (deoxidizer!).",
    "The use of a carefully controlled preheat."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which PWHT temperature range is normally recommended for 10CrMo9-10 (ISO/TR 14745)?",
    answers: ["550 - 600 °C.",
    "620 - 650 °C.",
    "630 - 680 °C.",
    "670 - 730 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is a typical carbon content in rimmed steel?",
    answers: ["0.015%.",
    "0.15%.",
    "0.25%.",
    "0.40%."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the carbon content in killed steel?",
    answers: ["Greater than 0.25%.",
    "At the most 0.25%.",
    "At least 0.35%.",
    "At the most 0.35%."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How does CaCO3 reduce the sulphur content in the metal of the welding pool in MMA (SMAW) or SAW welding?",
    answers: ["CaCO3 = CaO + CO2; FeS2 + 2CaO = FeO2 + 2CaS (slag);",
    "CaCO3 = CaO + CO2; FeS + CaO = FeO + CaS (slag);",
    "CaCO3 = CaO + CO2; Fe2S + CaO2 = 2FeO + CaS (slag);",
    "CaCO3 = CaO + CO2; Fe2S2 + 2CaO = 2FeO + 2CaS (slag)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When a weld is deposited to repair a crack on the surface of cast iron, the main concern is:",
    answers: ["Ensure the original mechanical strength of cast iron.",
    "Provide a malleable and ductile deposit.",
    "Stop the crack propagation and seal it with the liquid metal.",
    "Ensure deep penetration and a well-mixed weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which element combines with sulphur to reduce brittleness in steel?",
    answers: ["Oxygen.",
    "Silicon.",
    "Aluminium.",
    "Manganese."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What treatment can be applied to improve the ductility of the weld metal of martensitic steel parts?",
    answers: ["Quenching.",
    "Normalizing.",
    "Solid cementation.",
    "Liquid cementation."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the application of carbon and low alloy steels for high temperature service for a long time, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["All low alloy steels are suitable for working at the operating temperatures where structural steels are applied.",
    "Precipitation may occur, but no phase decomposition.",
    "Recrystallization may occur.",
    "Temperature is a more governing factor than dwell time for steel degradation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Considering the temperature variations that occur during fusion welding, indicate the correct option.",
    answers: ["When the joint is thick enough, the cooling time between 800 °C and 500 °C does not depend on the joint thickness.",
    "Cooling time between 800 °C and 500 °C does not depend on joint thickness.",
    "The greater the net welding energy in the weld, the greater the peak temperature value in the joint zone (Fusion zone + HAZ).",
    "The cooling rate in a HAZ region increases with sheet thickness and it also increases with preheat temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these steels would you select for cryogenic applications?",
    answers: ["Austenitic stainless steels.",
    "High carbon ferritic-pearlitic steels.",
    "Low carbon ferritic-pearlitic steels.",
    "Ferritic stainless steels."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Tick the correct alternative regarding porosity in the weld when welding aluminium and its alloys:",
    answers: ["The presence of hydrogen in the active zone causes porosity in the weld.",
    "The presence of the surface oxide layer does not cause porosity in the weld.",
    "The position and direction of welding do not influence the porosity level of the aluminium weld.",
    "The metal transfer mode of aluminium MIG welding has no influence on the porosity level of the weld."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the true statement regarding the microstructure of the fusion zone of low carbon and low alloy steels:",
    answers: ["Polygonal intergranular ferrite – these are small plates of ferrites that form inside the authentic grains (they are the most desired in welding due to their high ductility);",
    "Nuclear perlite at austenite grain boundaries. It is not one phase, but a mixture of two phases, ferrite and bainite;",
    "Side plates of ferrite – they constitute plates that nucleate at the grain boundaries of austenite and grow along well-defined planes within these grains;",
    "Nuclear martensite, preferentially at the austenite grain boundaries."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"High strength low alloy steel (HSLA) typically has a tensile strength of:",
    answers: ["200 MPa to 300 Mpa;",
    "300 MPa to 550 Mpa;",
    "600 MPa to 800 Mpa;",
    "more than 800 MPa."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The alloying element used in steel production that can eliminate the bad effects of overheating is:",
    answers: ["vanadium;",
    "chromium;",
    "manganese;",
    "silicon."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When producing semi-killed steels, a material such as ferro-silicon is added in order to:",
    answers: ["remove gases;",
    "improve tensile strength;",
    "reduce carbon content;",
    "increase the hardness of the final product."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"If manganese or cerium is added to a cast iron it will produce:",
    answers: ["grey cast iron;",
    "white cast iron;",
    "malleable cast iron;",
    "nodular cast iron."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which creep resistant steels are used at temperatures above 700 °C?",
    answers: ["Ferritic non-alloyed steels.",
    "Ferritic-pearlitic non-alloyed steels.",
    "Cr-Mo-V-W-Nb-Ti steels, type P91-P92.",
    "Low alloy steels of the Cr-Mo type."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which creep resistant steels are used at temperatures above 700 °C?",
    answers: ["Ferritic non-alloyed steels.",
    "Ferritic-pearlitic non-alloyed steels.",
    "Fully austenitic steels.",
    "Low alloy steels of the Cr-Mo type."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When vanadium is added to steel, it will increase:",
    answers: ["corrosion resistance;",
    "hardness;",
    "creep resistance;",
    "ductility."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these steels is recommended for service temperatures above 600 °C?",
    answers: ["13CrMo 4-5.",
    "13CrMoSi5-5.",
    "X10CrAl24.",
    "S235J2G3 (0,2% C + 1,4 Mn)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these steels is recommended for service temperatures above 600 °C?",
    answers: ["13CrMo 4-5.",
    "13CrMoSi5-5.",
    "X15CrNiSi25-20.",
    "S235J2G3 (0,2% C + 1,4 Mn)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Chromium is added in small amounts to alloy steels as a:",
    answers: ["ductility enhancer;",
    "machinability promoter;",
    "hardening element;",
    "creep resistance enhancer."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A low alloy steel:",
    answers: ["Always has alpha iron (ferrite) as the main constituent, regardless of C content;",
    "It presents different microstructures depending on the alloying elements and thermo-mechanical history;",
    "It has an austenitic structure at room temperature;",
    "It has low susceptibility to cold cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A low alloy steel:",
    answers: ["Always has alpha iron (ferrite) as the main constituent, regardless of C content;",
    "It presents a possibility of microstructural transformation in the solid state if a heat treatment is applied;",
    "It has an austenitic structure at room temperature;",
    "It has low susceptibility to cold cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How does austenite's larger grain size influence the position of TTT curves?",
    answers: ["The TTT curves are shifted to the right, as the transformation time from austenite (to pearlite) is longer in this case.",
    "The TTT curves are shifted to the left, as larger areas of grain boundaries, from where the transformation from austenite (to pearlite) begins, accelerate the transformation.",
    "They are shifted upwards, as they need a higher temperature for the transformation from austenite (to pearlite).",
    "The TTT curves are shifted downwards, since larger areas of grain boundaries, from where the transformation from austenite (to pearlite) begins, facilitate the transformation."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding fine-grained steels, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["All fine-grained steels have martensitic HAZ, due to their higher hardenability;",
    "Heat treatment for grain refining is done by austenization and rapid cooling (water or oil) to prevent grain growth;",
    "Annealing heat treatment is not suitable for grain refining;",
    "The yield strength of a fine-grained steel becomes even higher if it is cold worked, but its ductility drops."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"How does the granulation of the steels change during the hot rolling or forging operation?",
    answers: ["The granulation elongates, but no recrystallization takes place.",
    "The granulation elongates, accompanied by grain growth.",
    "The granulation elongates, but the recrystallization and regularization of the grains immediately take place.",
    "The grains elongate and break, creating a fine grain microstructure."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a way to increase the tensile strength of a structural steel:",
    answers: ["Grain refining by normalizing;",
    "Addition of alloying elements;",
    "Cold working;",
    "Hot working."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a way to increase the tensile strength of a structural steel:",
    answers: ["Grain refining by normalizing;",
    "Quenching heat treatment;",
    "Cold working;",
    "Hot working."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding heat-resistant high-alloy steels, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The addition of Cr and Ni is traditionally carried out to give these steels corrosion resistance;",
    "Adding lead to a high-alloy carbon steel not only improves its machinability, it also improves its creep resistance;",
    "The addition of Cr and Ni in steels aims to give them a martensitic matrix;",
    "The oxides that provide good resistance to oxidation and that are used in practice in different metal alloys are Cr2O3 and NiO3."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding heat-resistant high-alloy steels, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["Controlling the content of elements such as sulphur and phosphorus is important to minimize solidification cracks;",
    "Adding lead to a high-alloy carbon steel not only improves its machinability, it also improves its creep resistance;",
    "The addition of Cr and Ni in steels aims to give them a martensitic matrix;",
    "The oxides that provide good resistance to oxidation and that are used in practice in different metal alloys are Cr2O3 and NiO3."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding heat-resistant high-alloy steels, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The formation of protective oxide layers is essential for a good performance of steels at high temperature.",
    "Adding lead to a high-alloy carbon steel not only improves its machinability, it also improves its creep resistance;",
    "The addition of Cr and Ni in steels aims to give them a martensitic matrix;",
    "The oxides that provide good resistance to oxidation and that are used in practice in different metal alloys are Cr2O3 and NiO3."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What are the most commonly used alloying elements in copper alloys?",
    answers: ["Zn, Sn, Ni, Al, V e Si.",
    "Zn, Sn, Ni, Al, Si e Be.",
    "Zn, Sn, Ni, Al, Ar e Be.",
    "Zn, Sn, Ni, Al, W e Be."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The following welding practice is used to minimize intergranular corrosion of austenitic stainless steels:",
    answers: ["The use of filler metal with a carbon content of less than 0.3% (in this situation there is little carbon available to form chromium carbides);",
    "The use of filler metal with elements that have a greater affinity for chromium than carbon;",
    "The use of rigorous brushing of the weld surface after each pass;",
    "Annealing of the joint after being welded, with heating above sensitizing temperatures followed by rapid cooling (quenching)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a correct practice for welding austenitic stainless steels:",
    answers: ["They are of good weldability and do not need preheating;",
    "To maintain interpass temperature above 200 °C;",
    "Preheat as high as 400 °C;",
    "To use only austenitic electrodes."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a correct practice for welding austenitic stainless steels:",
    answers: ["To keep maximum interpass temperatures always below 200 °C, to avoid sensitization;",
    "To maintain interpass temperature above 200 °C;",
    "Preheat as high as 400 °C;",
    "To use only austenitic electrodes."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a correct practice for welding austenitic stainless steels:",
    answers: ["To apply the hammer peening to intermediate passes to reduce residual final stresses (except in thin sheets);",
    "To maintain interpass temperature above 200 °C;",
    "Preheat as high as 400 °C;",
    "To use only austenitic electrodes."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a correct practice for welding austenitic stainless steels:",
    answers: ["Welding with low welding energy (low heat input);",
    "To maintain interpass temperature above 200 °C;",
    "Preheat as high as 400 °C;",
    "To use only austenitic electrodes."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a correct practice for welding austenitic stainless steels:",
    answers: ["To use a low carbon or stabilized filler metal (due to risk of sensitization);",
    "To maintain interpass temperature above 200 °C;",
    "Preheat as high as 400 °C;",
    "To use only austenitic electrodes."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a correct practice for welding austenitic stainless steels:",
    answers: ["Whenever possible, use a filler metal that provides delta ferrite in the fusion zone structure (to minimize hot cracking);",
    "To maintain interpass temperature above 200 °C;",
    "Preheat as high as 400 °C;",
    "To use only austenitic electrodes."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a correct practice for welding austenitic stainless steels:",
    answers: ["To use a filler metal with low phosphorus, sulphur and silicon content (to minimize hot cracking);",
    "To maintain interpass temperature above 200 °C;",
    "Preheat as high as 400 °C;",
    "To use only austenitic electrodes."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a correct practice for welding austenitic stainless steels:",
    answers: ["Attention should always be paid to possible deformation of the welded joint;",
    "To maintain interpass temperature above 200 °C;",
    "Preheat as high as 400 °C;",
    "To use only austenitic electrodes."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding protective coatings applied by arc welding, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["Typically, tungsten carbide-type coatings are applied to gear shafts to improve wear resistance;",
    "Austenitic alloys are used when cavitation resistance is desired;",
    "Buttering is the process of forming a protective layer against corrosion;",
    "Usually the Weld Overlay (deposition of a filler metal upon a substrate) aims to ensure greater chemical resistance."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding protective coatings applied by arc welding, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["Typically, tungsten carbide-type coatings are applied to gear shafts to improve wear resistance;",
    "Inconel is an alloy that can be used as an anti-corrosion coating;",
    "Buttering is the process of forming a protective layer against corrosion;",
    "Usually the Weld Overlay (deposition of a filler metal upon a substrate) aims to ensure greater chemical resistance."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding protective coatings applied by arc welding, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["Typically, tungsten carbide-type coatings are applied to gear shafts to improve wear resistance;",
    "Abrasive wear coatings may show cracks without compromising application;",
    "Buttering is the process of forming a protective layer against corrosion;",
    "Usually the Weld Overlay (deposition of a filler metal upon a substrate) aims to ensure greater chemical resistance."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding techniques for welding cast iron, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["Cold welding techniques are performed at room temperature; therefore, no thermal stresses are generated;",
    "In the hot technique, the filler material must be nickel in order to quickly absorb the preheating heat;",
    "In the cold welding technique, low thermal stresses are generated (due to the application of appropriate methods), and the filler material is able to absorb it;",
    "In the hot technique, the preheating rate is not important, unlike the cooling rate, which must be done slowly to avoid temperature gradients in the part itself."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding techniques for welding cast iron, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["Cold welding techniques are performed at room temperature; therefore, no thermal stresses are generated;",
    "In the hot technique, the filler material must be nickel in order to quickly absorb the preheating heat;",
    "In the hot welding technique, thermal stresses generated are absorbed by the plastic deformation of the material as a whole (and not only by the HAZ).",
    "In the hot technique, the preheating rate is not important, unlike the cooling rate, which must be done slowly to avoid temperature gradients in the part itself."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What use is made of a Schaeffler diagram when welding stainless steels?",
    answers: ["If the first phase to solidify in the alloy is delta-ferrite, the development of duplex gamma + delta structure can be predicted from the Schaeffler diagram.",
    "By means of a Schaeffler diagram, the amount of delta-ferrite in weld metal can be predicted.",
    "The Schaeffler diagram predicts hydrogen solubility in weld metal.",
    "The Schaeffler diagram allows to predict the chemical composition of the filler metal based on the desired fusion zone microstructure."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What use is made of a Schaeffler diagram when welding stainless steels?",
    answers: ["If the first phase to solidify in the alloy is delta-ferrite, the development of duplex gamma + delta structure can be predicted from the Schaeffler diagram.",
    "By using the nickel and chromium equivalent values it is possible to predict the microstructure of weld metal.",
    "The Schaeffler diagram predicts hydrogen solubility in weld metal.",
    "The Schaeffler diagram allows to predict the chemical composition of the filler metal based on the desired fusion zone microstructure."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding nickel alloys, which of the following welding conditions should be followed?",
    answers: ["The material should be at room temperature before welding.",
    "To use narrower groove angles (40 - 60 degrees) to reduce angular distortion.",
    "Where possible, reduce the number of passes.",
    "The use a carefully controlled preheat."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding nickel alloys, which of the following welding conditions should be followed?",
    answers: ["To use large groove angles (60 - 80 degrees), since Ni alloys have low fluidity.",
    "To use narrower groove angles (40 - 60 degrees) to reduce angular distortion.",
    "Where possible, reduce the number of passes.",
    "The use a carefully controlled preheat."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which hardfacing material provides best impact resistance?",
    answers: ["Aluminium oxycarbide.",
    "Tungsten carbide.",
    "Chromium carbide.",
    "Austenitic manganese steels."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Annealing of a steel weld is a thermal procedure applied in order to:",
    answers: ["restore the initial microstructure, though with a degradation of mechanical properties;",
    "fully restore the microstructure of the metal to its pre-welded state;",
    "correct the excessive hardness and fragility of the material after hardening, increasing its ductility and shock resistance;",
    "partially restore the granular structure of the metal to its pre-welded state."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Annealing of a steel weld is a thermal procedure applied in order to:",
    answers: ["restore the initial microstructure, though with a degradation of mechanical properties;",
    "fully restore the microstructure of the metal to its pre-welded state;",
    "correct the excessive hardness and fragility of the material after hardening, increasing its ductility and shock resistance;",
    "change the microstructure, thus improving the mechanical properties."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following materials is sensitive to lamellar tearing? (Re = yield strength; A5 = elongation e ZD = reduction of area)",
    answers: ["Re = 235 N/mm²; A5 = 30%; ZD = 10%.",
    "Re = 460 N/mm²; A5 = 20%; ZD = 35%.",
    "Re = 235 N/mm²; A5 = 30%; ZD = 40%.",
    "Re = 235 N/mm²; A5 = 30%; ZD = 35%."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following materials is sensitive to lamellar tearing? (Re = yield strength; A5 = elongation e ZD = reduction of area)",
    answers: ["Re = 355 N/mm²; A5 = 25%; ZD = 10%.",
    "Re = 460 N/mm²; A5 = 20%; ZD = 35%.",
    "Re = 235 N/mm²; A5 = 30%; ZD = 40%.",
    "Re = 235 N/mm²; A5 = 30%; ZD = 35%."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the properties of the Heat Affected Zone (HAZ) in the welding of structural steels by fusion, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The HAZ is usually a region of high hardness and low toughness;",
    "The higher the heat input, the higher the cooling rate, resulting in harder metallurgical structures;",
    "The maximum hardness of the HAZ depends solely on the chemical composition of the steel (hardenability).",
    "In welding an alloy steel, the function of preheating is to reduce the hardness of the micro-constituents of the coarse HAZ."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"What has to be done when making openings in pressure vessels?",
    answers: ["To ensure full penetration of the weld connecting an inlet/outlet pipe or a nozzle with the pressurized component.",
    "To ensure that the weld connecting an inlet/outlet pipe or a nozzle with the pressurized component is fully radiographed.",
    "The weld connecting an inlet/outlet pipe or a nozzle with the pressurized component must be of the concave fillet type.",
    "A reinforcement must be done at the vicinity of the opening (area compensation method)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a standard used in the design of welded joints under static loading:",
    answers: ["ISO 5817;",
    " ISO 9692-2;",
    "Eurocode 3, Part 1.8;",
    "ISO-TR-581-2005."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The design standards for welded structures usually group welded joints into classes according to their degree of severity, each class with its reference S-N curve. Regarding the use of these curves, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["the effect of the welded joint edge preparation type is taken into account;",
    "\"the effect of \"\"backhand\"\" or \"\"forehand\"\" welding techniques is taken into account;\"",
    "the effect of joint profile improvement techniques is taken into account (hammering, weld toe smoothing by machining, TIG dressing, ...).",
    "the welded joint is generally evaluated by comparing the stress spectrum acting on the joint and the corresponding S-N reference curve."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the design of corner, T- or butt joints, it can be stated:",
    answers: ["Fillet welds must be sized exclusively for shear tension;",
    "The weld beads must have a lower mechanical strength than the plates, ensuring that the failure occurs in the weld and not in the joint component;",
    "The full penetration fillet weld mechanical strength is calculated from the triangle inscribed within its cross section;",
    "When designing welded joints, residual stresses also must be considered."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the design of corner, T- or butt joints, it can be stated:",
    answers: ["\"The minimum mechanical strength of the welded joint is maintained, as long as it has \"\"overmatch\"\" (weld strength higher than the strength of the base metal);\"",
    "The weld beads must have a lower mechanical strength than the plates, ensuring that the failure occurs in the weld and not in the joint component;",
    "The full penetration fillet weld mechanical strength is calculated from the triangle inscribed within its cross section;",
    "When designing welded joints, residual stresses also must be considered."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the design of corner, T- or butt joints, it can be stated:",
    answers: ["\"The specialist must be aware that even using joints with an \"\"overmatch\"\", the weld may fail before the base metal in the presence of defects;\"",
    "The weld beads must have a lower mechanical strength than the plates, ensuring that the failure occurs in the weld and not in the joint component;",
    "The full penetration fillet weld mechanical strength is calculated from the triangle inscribed within its cross section;",
    "When designing welded joints, residual stresses also must be considered."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the design of corner, T- or butt joints, it can be stated:",
    answers: ["The size of a full penetration butt weld is the smallest thickness of the connected plates;",
    "The full penetration fillet weld mechanical strength is calculated from the triangle inscribed within its cross section;",
    "Partial penetration welds can be used for joints subjected to bending load.",
    "When designing welded joints, residual stresses also must be considered."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the design of corner, T- or butt joints, it can be stated:",
    answers: ["When determining the size of full penetration welds, there is no need to consider pure tensile or compression stresses parallel to the weld axis;",
    "The full penetration fillet weld mechanical strength is calculated from the triangle inscribed within its cross section;",
    "Partial penetration welds can be used for joints subjected to bending load.",
    "When designing welded joints, residual stresses also must be considered."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"“Static fracture toughness” K1C is a material characteristic and is determined by:",
    answers: ["Tenacity test using notched specimens;",
    "Low cycle fatigue test;",
    "High cycle fatigue test;",
    "Excentric tensile or 3-point bending tests both performed with notched specimens with a previously generated fatigue crack."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"“Static fracture toughness” K1C is a material characteristic and is determined by:",
    answers: ["Tenacity test using notched specimens;",
    "Low cycle fatigue test;",
    "High cycle fatigue test;",
    "Static test on test specimens with a fatigue crack, which meet the conditions of planar deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture is higher when:",
    answers: ["the working temperature is high;",
    "the structure is stress relieved;",
    "the plate thickness is large;",
    "the CTOD-value (load) of the material is higher."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The risk for brittle fracture is higher when:",
    answers: ["the working temperature is high;",
    "the structure is stress relieved;",
    "the CTOD-value (load) of the material is lower;",
    "the CTOD-value (load) of the material is higher."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the mechanical properties of aluminium alloys for cryogenic applications it is correct to say that with the temperature decrease:",
    answers: ["their yield and tensile strengths will slightly increase; ",
    "their mechanical strength drops down;",
    "their elongation increases;",
    "\"their \"\"ductile-to-brittle\"\" transition lowers along with the reduction in temperature.\""],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the mechanical properties of aluminium alloys for cryogenic applications it is correct to say that with the temperature decrease:",
    answers: ["their elongation will go down;",
    "their mechanical strength drops down;",
    "their elongation increases;",
    "\"their \"\"ductile-to-brittle\"\" transition lowers along with the reduction in temperature.\""],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the mechanical properties of aluminium alloys for cryogenic applications it is correct to say that with the temperature decrease:",
    answers: ["their impact strength will not be changed much at all;",
    "their mechanical strength drops down;",
    "their elongation increases;",
    "\"their \"\"ductile-to-brittle\"\" transition lowers along with the reduction in temperature.\""],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the mechanical properties of aluminium alloys for cryogenic applications it is correct to say that with the temperature decrease:",
    answers: ["they do not exhibit any ductile-to-brittle transition;",
    "their mechanical strength drops down;",
    "their elongation increases;",
    "their impact strength will decrease."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The CTOD test is used:",
    answers: ["for material tenacity evaluation using notched specimens;",
    "to determine the opening displacement of the tip of a fatigue crack previously generated in the specimen;",
    "to determine the fatigue strength of notched specimens;",
    "to determine the ductile-to-brittle transition temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Linear Elastic Fracture Mechanics (LEFM), it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The LEFM is valid for cases of large-scale plastic deformation.",
    "Some examples of materials that can be analysed by LEFM are aluminium alloys, copper alloys, nickel alloys and austenitic stainless steels;",
    "Before unstable propagation, extensive stable tearing occurs;",
    "Total component failure can occur due to the presence of cracks, even under loading conditions well below the design specified level."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Linear Elastic Fracture Mechanics (LEFM), it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The LEFM is valid for cases of large-scale plastic deformation.",
    "Some examples of materials that can be analysed by LEFM are aluminium alloys, copper alloys, nickel alloys and austenitic stainless steels;",
    "Before unstable propagation, extensive stable tearing occurs;",
    "Structure components prone to brittle fracture failure cannot be dimensioned by applying the safety factor alone."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Linear Elastic Fracture Mechanics (LEFM), it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The LEFM is valid for cases of large-scale plastic deformation.",
    "Some examples of materials that can be analysed by LEFM are aluminium alloys, copper alloys, nickel alloys and austenitic stainless steels;",
    "Before unstable propagation, extensive stable tearing occurs;",
    "The safety factor, used in conventional designs for dimensioning welded joints, does not take into account brittle or rapid fracture failure."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a technique used to reduce the generation of thermal stresses:",
    answers: ["to start welding from the region of greatest restrictions in direction to those of lesser restrictions;",
    "to start welding from the region of lowest restriction in direction to those of higher restrictions;",
    "to apply post-weld vibration;",
    "to use post-heat treatment."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The Fitness-for-Purpose/Service assessments of a given welded component is applied:",
    answers: ["only to new structures, as structures in use may have complicating factors such as wear and as well as misuse;",
    "to structures in use whose inspection is not possible;",
    "exclusively to welded joints that contain planar discontinuities (cracks);",
    "to new structures that contain imperfections, to structures in use in which imperfections have appeared or structures at the end of their service life so that an extension of this life can be evaluated."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following Quality Requirements is common for the Comprehensive, Standard and Elementary quality levels according to ISO 3834?",
    answers: ["Testing shall be done before, during and after welding.",
    "Welders and welding operators shall be qualified by an appropriate test.",
    "Welding procedure specification (WPS) shall be qualified.",
    "Welding Engineer shall be qualified."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Regarding the term \"\"essential variables\"\", it can be stated:\"",
    answers: ["Essential variables may vary from standard to standard and if they are changed beyond the ranges indicated in the WPS, a new WPS must be qualified;",
    "These are welding procedure variables that can be modified only with the authorization of the welding engineer;",
    "They are defined by appropriate standards adopted in a country and have value ranges defined by consensus;",
    "Essential variables are variables that significantly affect the welding process stability, thus the welding quality."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Regarding the term \"\"essential variables\"\", it can be stated:\"",
    answers: ["The value range of each essential variable is a function of the values used in the qualification of the procedure, indicated in the WPQR;",
    "These are welding procedure variables that can be modified only with the authorization of the welding engineer;",
    "They are defined by appropriate standards adopted in a country and have value ranges defined by consensus;",
    "Essential variables are variables that significantly affect the welding process stability, thus the welding quality."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Regarding the term \"\"essential variables\"\", it can be stated:\"",
    answers: ["Essential variables are variables that significantly affect the mechanical properties of weldment (e.g., tensile strength, hardness and ductility);",
    "These are welding procedure variables that can be modified only with the authorization of the welding engineer;",
    "They are defined by appropriate standards adopted in a country and have value ranges defined by consensus;",
    "Essential variables are variables that significantly affect the welding process stability, thus the welding quality."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the term “Fitness-for-Service” assessment in the field of welding, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It’s a quantitative engineering assessment to verify that a new welded component is free from imperfections.",
    "It's a quantitative engineering evaluation to verify whether an in-service welded component is free from imperfections.",
    "It's a quantitative engineering evaluation performed to assess a risk for an in-service welded component to develop an imperfection.",
    "It's a quantitative engineering evaluation performed to assess the structural integrity of an in-service component containing a flaw or damage."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the term “Fitness-for-Service” assessment in the field of welding, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is an approach to choosing the most suitable consumables for the use;",
    "It is a methodology for choosing the most suitable welding processes for the use;",
    "This evaluation technique makes it possible to choose the best type of weld (but, fillet, point, ...) so that the welded product has a long service life.",
    "It is a philosophy that allows for a structure with defects to be still used, taking into account whether defects are critical or not for the functioning of the structure."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the term “Fitness-for-Service” assessment in the field of welding, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is an approach to choosing the most suitable consumables for the use;",
    "It is a methodology for choosing the most suitable welding processes for the use;",
    "This evaluation technique makes it possible to choose the best type of weld (but, fillet, point, ...) so that the welded product has a long service life.",
    "It is a philosophy that allows a welded structure, rejected because of the defect severity degree, to be used for other levels of stress (e.g., less critical)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the term “Fitness-for-Service” assessment in the field of welding, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is an approach to choosing the most suitable consumables for the use;",
    "It is a methodology for choosing the most suitable welding processes for the use;",
    "This evaluation technique makes it possible to choose the best type of weld (but, fillet, point, ...) so that the welded product has a long service life.",
    "The results of the destructive tests must be considered, but not as an absolute value, that is, without applying the concepts “accepted” and “not accepted”;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the term “Fitness-for-Service” assessment in the field of welding, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is an approach to choosing the most suitable consumables for the use;",
    "It is a methodology for choosing the most suitable welding processes for the use;",
    "This evaluation technique makes it possible to choose the best type of weld (but, fillet, point, ...) so that the welded product has a long service life.",
    "Inspection codes and standards should be used as they can reduce the risk of failure to a minimum, even if they do not guarantee full integrity;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the term “Fitness-for-Service” assessment in the field of welding, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is an approach to choosing the most suitable consumables for the use;",
    "It is a methodology for choosing the most suitable welding processes for the use;",
    "This evaluation technique makes it possible to choose the best type of weld (but, fillet, point, ...) so that the welded product has a long service life.",
    "It is possible to characterize the acceptability of a structure with an acceptable risk, to avoid the costs of scrapping or repair."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the concepts of repair welding:",
    answers: ["The same WPS of the original welding must be applied in the repair, not requiring requalification;",
    "Evaluate the possible generation of collateral problems, such as the generation of residual thermal stresses;",
    "Only the MMA/SMAW welding process is recommended to be applied in repair, whatever was the original welding process, due to its universality;",
    "After the repair welding is done, create a WPS for the work carried out, summarizing the experiences acquired and recommendations for preventive actions to ensure that the failure does not recur."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the concepts of repair welding:",
    answers: ["The same WPS of the original welding must be applied in the repair, not requiring requalification;",
    "After the excavation has been filled, the weldment should then undergo a complete retest using the same NDT techniques as previously used for the original weld.",
    "Only the MMA/SMAW welding process is recommended to be applied in repair due to its universality;",
    "After the repair welding is done, create a WPS for the work carried out, summarizing the experiences acquired and recommendations for preventive actions to ensure that the failure does not recur."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the concepts of repair welding:",
    answers: ["The same WPS of the original welding must be applied in the repair, not requiring requalification;",
    "After the flaw has been removed, a NDT inspection should be applied to verify the complete elimination of the flaw;",
    "Only the GTAW/TIG welding process is recommended to be applied in repair, whatever was the original welding process, due to its high quality;",
    "After the repair welding is done, create a WPS for the work carried out, summarizing the experiences acquired and recommendations for preventive actions to ensure that the failure does not recur."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the concepts of repair welding:",
    answers: ["The same WPS of the original welding must be applied in the repair, not requiring requalification;",
    "The welder/operator shall be qualified for repair welding;",
    "Only the GTAW/TIG welding process is recommended to be applied in repair, whatever was the original welding process, due to its high quality;",
    "After the repair welding is done, create a WPS for the work carried out, summarizing the experiences acquired and recommendations for preventive actions to ensure that the failure does not recur."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the concepts of repair welding:",
    answers: ["It is highly desirable that the repair weld to be done by the same welder/operator who has welded the original weld;",
    "Identify what was the root cause of the weld defect and whether it can happen again;",
    "The repair welding cannot be performed according to a qualified WPS, because of unpredictability of the repair process.",
    "The repaired weld never can get the same quality level as the original weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the concepts of repair welding:",
    answers: ["It is highly desirable that the repair weld to be done by the same welder/operator who has welded the original weld;",
    "Identify whether the defect is an inherent material defect, a manufacturing defect (during/after welding), or in-service failure;",
    "The repair welding cannot be performed according to a qualified WPS, because of unpredictability of the repair process;",
    "The repaired weld never can get the same quality level as the original weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the concepts of repair welding:",
    answers: ["It is highly desirable that the repair weld to be done by the same welder/operator who has welded the original weld;",
    "A welding repair procedure involves defect identification, defect removal, NDT, verification for a successful repair, and proper documentation for the repair to be done;",
    "The repair welding cannot be performed according to a qualified WPS, because of unpredictability of the repair process;",
    "The repaired weld never can get the same quality level as the original weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the concepts of repair welding:",
    answers: ["It is highly desirable that the repair weld to be done by the same welder/operator who has welded the original weld;",
    "For cast steels, the preheat temperature is determined by the carbon equivalent of base material and/or the thickness of the piece;",
    "The repair welding cannot be performed according to a qualified WPS, because of unpredictability of the repair process;",
    "The repaired weld never can get the same quality level as the original weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Crack removal requires proper knowledge and techniques. Choose the correct alternative among the statements below:",
    answers: ["The crack should not be identified with Liquid Penetrant Testing, so as not to contaminate the weld region;",
    "Use consumables with greater elongation and tensile strength of at least twice that of the cracked material;",
    "If the crack has the beginning and the end inside the part, the most suitable welding sequence is to pull the welds from the ends to the middle of the crack;",
    "Repaired weld shall be re-checked by another NDT method different from that used for original weld to enhance the test objectivity. "],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Crack removal requires proper knowledge and techniques. Choose the correct alternative among the statements below:",
    answers: ["The crack should not be identified with Liquid Penetrant Testing, so as not to contaminate the weld region;",
    "Use consumables with greater elongation and tensile strength of at least twice that of the cracked material;",
    "If the crack extends to the end of the part, the most suitable welding sequence is to pull the weld from the beginning of the crack to its end;",
    "Repaired weld shall be re-checked by another NDT method different from that used for original weld to enhance the test objectivity. "],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What step should you take first if you are responsible for a repair welding?",
    answers: ["Determine the chemical composition and characteristics of the material.",
    "Qualify the repair welding procedure by welding a test piece in accordance with the original manufacturing procedure.",
    "an X-ray diffraction analysis to assess residual stress;",
    "a detailed analysis of similar cases (materials with the same chemical composition, similar loading, ...), proposed solutions and final results."],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What step should you take first if you are responsible for a repair welding?",
    answers: ["Determine the size of the defect and choose a process for its complete removal.",
    "Qualify the repair welding procedure by welding a test piece in accordance with the original manufacturing procedure.",
    "an X-ray diffraction analysis to assess residual stress;",
    "a detailed analysis of similar cases (materials with the same chemical composition, similar loading, ...), proposed solutions and final results."],
    correctAnswer:"",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The repair of a defective weld on a part with unknown metallurgical characterization must be preceded by, at least:",
    answers: ["a finite element analysis to know the stresses at the area;",
    "an examination, even simple, to know the chemical composition and characteristics of the material in order to select preheating and compatible consumables;",
    "an X-ray diffraction analysis to assess residual stress;",
    "a detailed analysis of similar cases (materials with the same chemical composition, similar loading, ...), proposed solutions and final results."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The repair of a defective weld on a part with unknown metallurgical characterization must be preceded by, at least:",
    answers: ["a finite element analysis to know the stresses at the area;",
    "a visual examination to assess the type of damage and to select a procedure that does not exacerbate existing problems;",
    "an X-ray diffraction analysis to assess residual stress;",
    "a detailed analysis of similar cases (materials with the same chemical composition, similar loading, ...), proposed solutions and final results."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"If the weld was made using the TIG process (141) at the root, with 3 more passes by MIG/MAG (131/135) and, finally, 5 more passes by SAW (12), the WPS qualification is valid:",
    answers: ["only for the process that was used to make the root pass;",
    "for all processes together;",
    "for each process separately, observing the limit range of the size of the deposited layer;",
    "only for the process responsible for the greatest thickness of the deposited metal."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In some standards for procedure and performance qualification, the face and root bend test is specified for thinner test plates and side bend test for thicker plates. What is the reason for this?",
    answers: ["The application of force in the case of face or root bending takes place over the reinforcement whose geometry is not standardized, impairing the repeatability of the results.",
    "Face and root reinforcements prevent the weld from opening to get access to internal discontinuities.",
    "Side bending is easy to be standardized.",
    "Face/root bending of thick plates would require very high power as well as an equipment/dies of a very high mechanical strength."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"During the qualification of a welding procedure, it is permissible to use:",
    answers: ["more than one type of joint as long as it is of the same thickness as the base metal;",
    "different types of welds as long as they are applied to the same type of joint;",
    "only one welder (he/she must be qualified);",
    "more than one welding process."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"During the qualification of a welding procedure, it is permissible to use:",
    answers: ["more than one type of joint as long as it is of the same thickness as the base metal;",
    "different types of welds as long as they are applied to the same type of joint;",
    "only one type of base material (on the contrary, it would be another procedure);",
    "more than one welder as long as he/she is qualified."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"During the qualification of a welding procedure, it is permissible to use:",
    answers: ["more than one type of joint as long as it is of the same thickness as the base metal;",
    "different types of welds as long as they are applied to the same type of joint;",
    "only one welder (he/she must be qualified);",
    "more than one type of base material."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"}
];